if you didn't already know rogue offers
some of the best home gym equipment
available on the market but because of
that high quality their barbells tend to
be on the higher end of the price
spectrum however i just got my hands on
the rogue echo 2.0
it has a tensile strength rating of 190
000 psi
a medium knurling that's forgiving on
your hands bushings that allow the
sleeves to spin
and the best part of it it's pretty
affordable
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back again
in the barbie garage gym and for today's
review i've got the rogue echo 2.0
in this video i'm going to break down
this barbell and everything it has to
offer from the price some features pros
and cons and of course who should buy it
and who shouldn't buy it but before we
get started gotta let you know as always
we have reviewed a ton of barbells on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just do a quick google search
type in barbend best barbells you can
read all for yourself which ones we like
the best
[Music]
okay so what do i like about the rogue
echo 2.0 well i'm going to start this
off with what i think is the biggest
determining factor when buying a barbell
the tensile strength
the rogue echo 2.0 has a tensile
strength rating of 190 000 psi
man okay now what does that mean well
essentially tensile strength is how much
weight and force a barbell can handle
before it begins to bend or break
the lack of a center knurling and the
bronze bushings make this ideal for
those crossfitters and olympic
weightlifters out there as does the
medium knurling it's not going to tear
up your hands too bad especially during
those high rep exercises and probably
the best thing of all is that it is
available at a budget price this is one
of the cheapest barbells that rogue has
to offer and it's nearly identical to
the ohio bar but at a much lower price
which makes this really appealing in my
eyes for those home gym weight thrashers
out there watching
okay now this is not a disney fairy tale
there are a few potential cons that you
could run into with this barbell let's
start with the knurling yeah that medium
style knurling is really nice for a lot
of you out there but there's also some
of you guys watching that want a deeper
cut on your barbell now remember this is
a multi-purpose bar it's pretty standard
as far as knurling goes on a bar like
this one it's not specific for power
lifting you know those power bars are
going to be much deeper cut on the
knurling to get a better grip while
you're bench pressing the lack of a
center knurling could be problematic
when you're going to squat and you're
putting the bar up here on your traps
you won't get as much of a grip as you
would with that center knurling and
there's also some people who like that
center knurling while you're power
cleaning so it can kind of stick to your
chest a little bit more once you raise
it up here the lack of double knurl
markings on this barbell was a bit
surprising to me
you know typically with a multi-purpose
bar like this one
you'll find the double knurl markings so
if you don't know what that is
the inner marking is for the widest grip
while you're power lifting like bench
pressing in that outer marking is for
the widest grip while you're doing
olympic style lifts like power cleaning
it also would be cool if this barbell
came in another finish other than just
the regular zinc
rogue offers that in some of their other
barbells and you know this regular zinc
will help in terms of fighting off
corrosion
but not as well as a fully stainless
steel bar can
and another thing i'd really like to see
here is a longer warranty this only has
a one year warranty some other barbells
from rogue like the ohio bar for
instance have a limited lifetime
warranty this one only comes with a one
year warranty
okay so head over to the rogue fitness
website and you'll find the rogue echo
2.0 is priced around 270 dollars this is
a great deal once you consider how much
weight this bar can really handle a lot
of times barbells of this price feature
a tensile strength rating that is much
lower and compared to the rest of the
rogue barbells this is one of the
cheapest ones
so standard shipping and taxes are only
going to add about 50 bucks or so to
your purchase
putting you around
total
now i want to set something straight 300
is still a lot of money in my eyes but
once you consider the quality of this
barbell
it's a bit of a steal rogue also allows
you to split your purchase up into
interest-free payments through either
pay later from paypal or through a firm
if you don't have a firm account you
need to make one they are gonna run a
credit score check on you but don't
worry it's not gonna affect your score
at all once that's done you can log into
either one of your accounts and it's
going to show you your payments that are
going to be around 80 bucks or so split
up into four interest-free payments
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
that went into the rogue echo 2.0 and
don't let that low price tag fool you
this is a high quality barbell it does
have a zinc finish on here which is
going to allow it to fight off some of
that rust and corrosion over time the
bronze bushings and the sleeves allow
them to spin which is ideal for any of
those exercises that require that spin
the 16.4 inch loading sleeves and the
28.5 millimeter diameter pretty standard
in practice and this medium style
knurling right here is going to be great
for those high rep movements because
it's not going to tear up your hands and
feel like you're rubbing your hand on a
cheese ring
okay so who should purchase the rogue
echo 2.0 well if you're new to
weightlifting you're going to really
enjoy the fact that this barbell does
have a knurling that's on the moderate
side of things and it's not going to
tear up your hands too bad
plus the 190 000 tinsel strength rating
means you can grow with this bar or if
you've already been lifting for quite
some time this is a good option for you
as well and when it comes to olympic
style lifts or crossfit style lifts this
is a really good option for you to
consider okay so who might not want to
purchase the rogue echo 2.0 well if
you're looking for a powerball with a
really abrasive knurling well bad news
for your friend this is not the barbell
for you because it is not a power bar
plus the knurling here is on the
moderate side of things
this may be more of a personal
preference but the lack of the center
knurling as well as the lack of outer
knurling markings
might not be ideal for some of you guys
out there and this bar also only has a
one year warranty now it does feel
really sturdy and it does have a tensile
strength rating of 190 000 psi
that still might be a red flag for some
of you buyers out there
all right guys that about wraps up
today's video over the rogue echo 2.0
this is an awesome barbell to consider
for your home gym because of its high
versatility high tensile strength rating
plus it's available at a price other
barbells are of lesser quality it really
doesn't matter what you throw at this
thing it's gonna be able to handle it
as always guys thank you for watching i
hope this video was really helpful as
you look for your next barbell stay on
the lookout for my next review but in
the meantime head over to barbin.com and
you can read over everything we
discussed here today just search bar
bend rogue echo 2.0 review it's going to
pull right up for you now what are you
doing go get your workout in i'll see
you later
[Music]
so
you